# Fabian Camilo Peña

Colombia



linkedin.com/in/fabiancpl



fabiancpl91@gmail.com



+573173780011

### Summary

I have a master degree in Information Engineering with focus on visual analytics and machine learning. I have implemented data analytics and big data solutions in contexts such as smart cities, transportation, environmental management, tax administration and public health. In addition, I have experience in software development and cloud computing.

### **Experience**



#### Lead Data Scientist

Analytic Lab

Feb 2019 - Present (1 year 4 months +)

Design and development of a smart cities platform for transportation and environmental management. Lead a team composed by data scientists and software developers building machine learning models, data visualizations and microservices based on multiple open-source technologies running on Google Cloud Platform.

#### **Course Instructor**

EUD - Fundación de Egresados de la Universidad Distrital

Dec 2017 - Present (2 years 6 months +)

Teaching activities for the big data and data analytics course. Development of theoretical and practical sessions with a duration of 80 hours.

### Research Assistant

Universidad de Los Andes

Jan 2017 - Dec 2018 (2 years)

Design and development of solutions based on data analytics and big data for the CAOBA Alliance and its partners, principally government companies. Implementation of machine learning models, data transformation and visualization software using open-source technologies.

## Software Developer

Green Tech

Apr 2016 - Jun 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Software development and support for electronic payment systems. Design and development of frontend on AngularJs and REST webservices.

#### Project Lead

Of Business

Nov 2014 - Apr 2016 (1 year 6 months)

Management and implementation of projects of virtualization and information security. Administration of VMware, diagnostic of application and database servers and implementation of domain controller and terminal server hostings.



**IBM** 

Jul 2014 - Nov 2014 (5 months)

Software development for the National Savings Fund (Fondo Nacional de Ahorro) based on Java Enterprise Edition, REST webservices and Javascript. I was also involved in the development of store procedures in DB2.

### Software Developer

One-Click S.A.S

Jun 2012 - Oct 2013 (1 year 5 months)

Requirement analysis and software development based on Java Enterprise Edition, Vaadin, Oracle and IBM WebSphere Application Server.

#### **Education**

Universidad Nacional de Colombia

Probability and Basic Inference 2020 - 2020

Universidad de Los Andes

Master's degree, Information Engineering 2017 - 2019

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas

Bachelor's degree, Systems Engineering 2008 - 2015

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Coursera
  UBES9ZA4J6K6
- Google Cloud Platform Big Data and Machine Learning Fundamentals Coursera
  7FCQ3G6JYNY8
- Modernizing Data Lakes and Data Warehouses with GCP Coursera 1fb43d52a837d53ae9d7123b93f4a64a

#### **Honors & Awards**

- IEEE Latin America and the Caribbean Discretional Director's Award IEEE Region 9

  Mar 2015
- IEEE Computer Society Richard E. Merwin Scholarship IEEE Computer Society

  Apr 2013

#### **Skills**

Data Science • Machine Learning • Software Development • Programming • Project Management • Project Planning • Entrepreneurship • Research • Data Analysis • Data Mining